Brian Mwendwa



brianmwendwa.mu@gmail.com



+254796898480



linkedin.com/in/brian-mwendwa-25326a173



https://mwendwa.netlify.app/

Summary

I am naturally inquisitive; I like to learn and explore new ideas. I believe in the inevitability of change and work towards adapting to change. I am a passionate software developer with experience in JavaScript, MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Cloud Development and Architecture. The fable of the Crow and the Pitcher is what best represents my professional journey.

Experience



Software Developer - Freelance

Pemtergroup Kenya

Jan 2021 - Jul 2021 (7 months)

- 1. Collaborated with a team of developers to design the data and presentation layer of the web application's front-end with Material ui and Figma.
- 2. Used additional JavaScript libraries such as React Context API and Recoil to manage the web application's state, derive computed data from the state of the system, and make asynchronous API calls.
- 3. Tested and updated the web application with Jest so that it can be used on all web browsers.

Web Developer - Intern

Conceptshub

Jan 2021 - Mar 2021 (3 months)

- 1. Designed wireframes with Figma and Adobe illustrator.
- 2. Worked with the development team to develop backend and front-end applications with Express, Mongo and React JS.
- 3. Deployed web applications through Continuous Integration/Development on GitHub.
- 4. Collaborated with developers to implement new web features.



Web Developer - Freelance

vulnerablechildrenconcernskenya

Oct 2020 - Oct 2021 (1 year 1 month)

- 1. Wrote well designed, testable, efficient code by using best software development practices like High Cohesion - Low Coupling to reduce module complexion.
- 2. Built website layout/user interfaces by using standard ReactJS components as well as React Hooks integrating data from various back-end services and databases.
- 3. Intergrated a backend email service with nodemailer.



🕍 Information Technology Intern

Kenya Ministry of Agriculture, Livestock, Fisheries and Cooperatives Mar 2019 - Jun 2019 (4 months)

1. Handled network routing and configuration for various departments within the Ministry.

- 2. Installed and configured computer hardware, software, systems, networks, printers, and scanners.
- 3. Provided technical support across the company.

Education

Africa International University

Bachelor's degree, IT 2018 - 2021

KCA University

CCNA, System, Networking, and LAN/WAN Management/Manager 2019 - 2020

Starehe Boys' Centre and School

High School Certificate (KCSE) Jan 2013 - Nov 2017

Licenses & Certifications

Blockchain Intro - IBM gs180234bsit@aiu.ac.ke

Usable Security - Coursera

- Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing and Switching (CCNA) Cisco
- API IBM
- Node.js V2 IBM
- (A) JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures freeCodeCamp
- Modern JavaScript for ReactJS ES6 Udemy UC-1ad2b96d-feef-45a1-bd8c-19f98d0a967b
- **AWS Services for Solutions Architect 2021** Udemy UC-6947d87c-dca5-4d93-8dbd-1d2f959a00b1

Skills

Programming • React.js • MongoDB • JavaScript • Web Development

Honors & Awards

Certificate of Participation - Kenya Red Cross Youth

Aug 2016

Was enrolled as a Youth Member of the Kenya Red Cross Society, joining others all over the world to help the sick and suffering.